<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iA</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ia.net/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ia.net</link>
	<description>We Architect Information</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 07:38:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.10</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">135361690</site>	<item>
		<title>End Procrastination</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/topics/end-procrastination</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Reichenstein]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 12:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?p=7730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The most influential companies in the world put all their energy into getting us to click, react, and consume. If you work on a computer, procrastination awaits you everywhere, all the time. How do you beat it and get things done? </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/end-procrastination">End Procrastination</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The most influential companies in the world put all their energy into getting us to click, react, and consume. If you work on a computer, procrastination awaits you everywhere, all the time. How do you beat it and get things done?</p>
<div class="article__img"><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Procrastination-scaled.jpg" alt="Procratination. Photo by Nguyen Linh: @nklphoto on Unsplash" width="" height="" class="" /><figcaption>Smoking is the prototype of a neurotic delaying technique: Pretends to inspire, ends up exhausting us and severely hurting us long term. And for some psycho-socio-bio-neuroscientific reasons it&#8217;s not easy to stop. Photo: Nguyen Linh.</figcaption></div>
<section class="article__box">
<div class="article__box-text">
<div>
<p>There is procrastination<sup id="fnref-7730-1"><a href="#fn-7730-1" class="jetpack-footnote">1</a></sup> as in everyday trouble to get started. There is procrastination as in trouble finishing things. And there is procrastination as a weeklong, monthlong, yearlong, self-harming self-torture.<sup id="fnref-7730-2"><a href="#fn-7730-2" class="jetpack-footnote">2</a></sup> The first two are annoying but common. The last one can threaten your very existence.<sup id="fnref-7730-3"><a href="#fn-7730-3" class="jetpack-footnote">3</a></sup></p>
<p>If you are doing just fine but you sometimes just can&#8217;t get started or avoid finishing your tasks, there are simple techniques to get started.</p>
<h2>1. Understand the word</h2>
<p>Words we don&#8217;t understand work like a spell. Understanding the words is the first step to breaking their magic. The word procrastination sounds long, winding, sophisticated, complicated, and hard to crack. It&#8217;s as if it was artfully coined not to be understood. Procrastinating means you&#8217;re delaying: &#8220;Pro crastinus&#8221; means &#8220;for tomorrow&#8221;. How do you avoid delays? By starting. How do you start?</p>
<h2>2. Break it up</h2>
<p>If you procrastinate, you don&#8217;t do anything refined, mysterious, or scientifically inevitable. You delay. You delay starting. Or you delay finishing things. Do you want to overcome your delays? Thinking is the first thing we avoid. Thinking is highly unpleasant. But it&#8217;s necessary to get oversight and prepare the right action.</p>
<p>Split your work into reasonable chunks. Get started choosing the least painful, then choose the next. Finish task by task. Why think, why not just race in? You think to prepare. Don&#8217;t hack away, sharpen the axe before cutting the tree.</p>
<h2>3. Find inspiration (don&#8217;t wait for it)</h2>
<p>Inspiration can come at unexpected times. But usually, it involves an activity like talking to someone, walking, showering, and, yes, going to the toilet.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Don&#8217;t wait for inspiration. It comes while one is working.&#8221; –Henry Matisse
</p></blockquote>
<p>Most often, you find inspiration when you are already at work. Literally, &#8220;in-spiration&#8221; means &#8220;breathing in.&#8221; To get inspired, take a breath and start.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Go after [inspiration] with a club.&#8221; –Jack London
</p></blockquote>
<h2>4. Separate procrastination and addiction</h2>
<p>Your <em>well deserved</em> cigarette break<sup id="fnref-7730-4"><a href="#fn-7730-4" class="jetpack-footnote">4</a></sup> or your <em>needed</em> glass of Bordeau won&#8217;t <em>load your batteries</em>. Unless you <em>are</em> already working, and you have gotten tired <em>from</em> working, resigning to your addictions will not start or speed you up. Consuming consumes your attention.</p>
<p>Lying to yourself about that will exhaust and depress you even more. Fighting addiction and procrastination is a two-front battle that you will most likely lose.</p>
<h2>5. Get active</h2>
<p>Even if you are not addicted, taking a passive, energy-draining time-out like drinking alcohol, smoking, watching your series, or browsing /r/wtf/ will not get you in the mood. It will <em>delay</em> things. It will shorten your time, increase the stress and wear you out. The only excuse to do something other than the thing you need to do is do another thing on your list.</p>
<p>Most of the tech industry is designed to turn you into a vegetable. They invite you to click on things until you click ads, and then they try to make you click ads until you click buy. Since many of us work on the screen, it can be confusing to discern between consumption and production. Here is a guideline:</p>
<ul>
<li>No one came back from YouTube feeling fresh and energized. </li>
<li>No one peeled out motivated and happy after two hours of scrolling through Instagram. </li>
<li>No one ever got inspired to finish things up after a Netflix Bonanza.</li>
<li>Buying some stuff online is not very productive. It&#8217;s consuming.</li>
</ul>
<p>You still can&#8217;t find the spark to get the fire started? Giving yourself an excuse to consume is pouring water on your matches.</p>
<h2>6. Change perspectives</h2>
<p>Yes, your body is constantly playing tricks on you. Yes, it fools you into believing what isn&#8217;t the case. It blinds you from seeing what is. And it directs you to get fast rewards.</p>
<p>Your reward system is getting hacked, and you are being made a slave of yourself. And before you know it, you&#8217;re on a circus bike in a psychodrome, racing in circles, and you don&#8217;t know how to slow down without falling on your helmet. Now, that&#8217;s one way to describe it. Attributing your delays to some unalterable biochemical processes and giving them scientific names will make your delaying seem scientifically inevitable.</p>
<p>Yeah, but really, a science is one perspective on the world. Biology, physics, chemistry&#8230; each is just <em>one</em> way to look at and describe reality. Don&#8217;t let your inner neuroscientist discourage the unmeasurable, unweighable, uncountable free philosophical self inside you.</p>
<p>You are more than the sum of your cells. And you are not a dog. You don&#8217;t need to run after every stick that flies through the air.</p>
<h2>7. Face the truth</h2>
<p>Do you think that there are some complicated fears of failure deep down, maybe holding you back with their invisible tentacles? So, that&#8217;s why you need to first check out some videos of stupid people lighting their ghost jalapeño farts? Do you think ghost jalapeño farts will get you on track? Here are three more exercises that have never ignited any meaningful action:</p>
<ul>
<li>Checking up on old lost friends on Facebook</li>
<li>Being jealous of people that seem happy</li>
<li>Pretending to be morally offended</li>
<li>Pretending to be good looking</li>
<li>Pretending to be productive</li>
<li>Pretending to be successful</li>
<li>Discussing with strangers</li>
<li>Pretending to be healthy</li>
<li>Pretending to be amused</li>
<li>Pretending to be funny</li>
<li>Reading the comments</li>
<li>Reacting to comments</li>
<li>Pretending to be rich</li>
<li>Pretending to care</li>
<li>Reading the news</li>
<li>Reading tweets</li>
<li>Liking tweets</li>
<li>Pretending </li>
</ul>
<p>If you work, you need breaks&#8230; If you work at a screen, a break means getting away from the screen. When? How often?  How long? Depending on what you do and as you feel fit. Some need to stop every 25 Minutes. Some can work for 40 Minutes.<sup id="fnref-7730-5"><a href="#fn-7730-5" class="jetpack-footnote">5</a></sup></p>
<h2>So, what&#8217;s the trick?</h2>
<p>There is no other trick to do what needs to be done—other than getting started. If you still think about your task and&#8230;</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8230;you don&#8217;t know where to begin&#8230; </li>
<li>&#8230;you feel like you&#8217;re being suffocated&#8230;</li>
<li>&#8230;you imagine that someone is holding a fork right in front of your throat and if you take just one step&#8230;</li>
</ul>
<p>&#8230;then is the time to take that step and discover that there is no fork.</p>
<p>Once you have gotten started, most things that seem unbearable or impossible turn out to be just something you do. And most likely, making the dishes, making that call, writing that mail turns out to feel good. Moving from passive to active feels good. Making order out of chaos is liberating. Getting stuff done feels great.</p>
<p>Turn your attention away from consumption to an active task, no matter how minor. Don&#8217;t ask yourself if you feel like doing it. Do it and do it right so you feel it. And then, when you are done and still in motion—do <em>not</em> take a pause. Do that other thing that was suffocating you before, right after.</p>
<p>Procrastination sounds sophisticated, complicated, and hard to get out of. Deep procrastination is a serious problem that needs outside help. Common procrastination is an ubiquitous glittering lure but it is not that big of a deal. It just means that you delay something a bit unpleasant for something a bit more pleasant. And if you want to move forward, whether it&#8217;s in an estimate, a design, or a text—don&#8217;t wait until you feel like it. To overcome delays: get started. Now.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn-7730-1">
Merriam Webster: &#8220;English speakers borrowed the word in the 16th century from Latin procrastinatus, which itself evolved from the prefix pro-, meaning &#8216;forward,&#8217; and crastinus, meaning &#8216;of tomorrow.&#8217;&#160;<a href="#fnref-7730-1">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7730-2">
&#8220;Over time, chronic procrastination has not only productivity costs, but measurably destructive effects on our mental and physical health, including chronic stress, general psychological distress and low life satisfaction, symptoms of depression and anxiety, poor health behaviors, chronic illness and even hypertension and cardiovascular disease.&#8221; <a class= "no-underline" href=" https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/25/smarter-living/why-you-procrastinate-it-has-nothing-to-do-with-self-control.html">Why You Procrastinate</a>, NYT.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7730-2">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7730-3">
If you are in a self-torture spiral that you can&#8217;t get out of by yourself, get help. You are likely avoiding reality to not deal with yourself. You are occupying your mind so it doesn&#8217;t need to hear itself. Don&#8217;t feel ashamed about it. Admit it to yourself, get help, and get well. It&#8217;s more common than you think.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7730-3">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7730-4">
What, smoking <em>does</em> help you? Let an experienced smoker refresh your memory of what happens when you smoke: &#8220;The short-term effects of tobacco are a momentary stimulation followed by a state of withdrawal and reduced brain activity, bad breath, fatigue, and dizziness, dulling the senses of taste and smell, coughing, shortness of breath, increased blood pressure, increased heart rate, decreased blood flow, nausea, headaches.&#8221; Maybe you&#8217;re special. –<a class= "no-underline" href=" https://cbqmethod.com/effects-of-smoking-on-your-body/l">Quit Smoking</a>, CBQ&#160;<a href="#fnref-7730-4">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7730-5">
&#8220;The frequency of your break depends, too, on what you&#8217;re doing. Coding is very different from emailing, which is different from writing. As long as you stay within the guardrails of 90 minutes, you should be okay.&#8221; <a class= "no-underline" href=" https://www.inc.com/neil-patel/when-how-and-how-often-to-take-a-break.html">When, How, and How Often to Take a Break</a>, Inc.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7730-5">&#8617;</a>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/end-procrastination">End Procrastination</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7730</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Apps and Coffee</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/topics/on-apps-and-coffee</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Reichenstein]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 07:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?p=7558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>No matter how many times developers compare their apps to coffee... apps are not coffee. The question is not: How many coffees does an app cost. It's: How many apps does a cup of coffee cost? And the answer is: Apps are not coffee but coffee machines.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/on-apps-and-coffee">On Apps and Coffee</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No matter how many times developers compare their apps to coffee&#8230; apps are not coffee. The question is not: How many coffees does an app cost? It&#8217;s: How many apps does a coffee cost? And the answer is: Apps are not coffee but coffee machines.</p>
<div class="article__img"><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/FC7V_44XEAM_PLn.jpeg" alt="" width="" height="" class="" /></div>
<section class="article__box">
<div class="article__box-text">
<div>
<p>I woke up the other day, thinking about app pricing and the tragically unsuccessful cup-of-coffee-comparison.<sup id="fnref-7558-1"><a href="#fn-7558-1" class="jetpack-footnote">1</a></sup></p>
<p>A cup of coffee ($5 to $10) has a <a href="https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=7SM2Jrot-ZM">calculable</a>, comparable, and comprehensive value. The farming → the processing → the transport → the roasting → the grinding → the brewing → the shop → the milk, and the barista. Global distances! Hard work! Precious time! Those things don&#8217;t come for free. And then it all smells so nice! Nice things cost! 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 dollars? Here&#8217;s my money!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to convince coffee drinkers to pay for coffee. They already want one. To make them happy just hand them over that cup. If you know how to brew a better coffee than Starbucks, which is not a high bar, you can expect some people to come in and order daily.</p>
<h2>The price of an app</h2>
<p>Apps are a different story. The value of an app is a confusing matter. What an app is worth to you can become dramatically personal, contextual, and time-sensitive—it depends on who needs that app—for what, for whom, why, how, when, and by when. One and the same app can mean anything from 0 to +n$ benefit, 0 to 50 spikes of blood pressure, serotonin, dopamine, adrenaline, depending on who uses it for what, for whom, why, how, when, and by when. Unfortunately, we just have to make one price for all.</p>
<p>How can it be that you get feature-loaded apps from Google for free and then you need to pay for that simple stuff from iA?<sup id="fnref-7558-2"><a href="#fn-7558-2" class="jetpack-footnote">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Software is a tough sell, and it has a tough crowd. Users expect fast, bug-free apps that serve their exact needs, now, for free, forever. They compare your features and your price to the $0.– offers from Google &amp; Co and frown when they see that it requires more than just their private data.</p>
<p>Compared to zero, 5 dollars per year, meaning 41.666 cents per month <em>is</em> expensive. Next to free, anything above 0 becomes infinitely expensive and diabolically greedy.</p>
<h2>Small apps: High quality, fast cycles, real support</h2>
<p>Users expect more privacy, higher quality, and better support from smaller developers. And smaller prices. 5 bucks? Who do you think you are? Starbucks?</p>
<p>You know that your mail about that export bug in Excel won&#8217;t make a dent in Microsoft&#8217;s universe.<sup id="fnref-7558-3"><a href="#fn-7558-3" class="jetpack-footnote">3</a></sup> Write a big feature request at <em>Indie Inc.</em>, and your expectation mirrors your feelings when asking for extra sugar at the local coffee shop.</p>
<p><em>Indie Inc</em> expected to regularly update their software with new features and battle each other in a monthly chess boxing K1 feature deathmatch with Silicon Valley. Ah, haha, look, here they jump again at each other&#8217;s throats on Twitter! App A copied app B&#8217;s button color!</p>
<h2>Big apps: Low quality, slow cycles, no support</h2>
<p>Big apps usually come with a lot of features, but they are not known for big innovation. Innovation is either copied from startups, or it&#8217;s directly M&amp;A&#8217;s job. Big apps already have feature bloat, every addition makes them harder to use and even buggier. Word added Dark Mode <a href="https://supertekboy.com/2020/11/30/microsoft-word-editor-goes-full-dark-mode/">ten years after Indie Inc</a>. In 2021 tech blogs get excited that Word is now <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/2/9/22274181/microsoft-word-dark-mode-canvas-update-beta">making their Dark Mode darker</a>. In another 25 years, maybe, it will be like Dale B. Cooper&#8217;s ideal cup.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article__img"><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/10_TPB_CooperLoveCoffee_1003_Breakfast.png" alt="Black as midnight on a moonless night" width="" height="" class="" /><figcaption>Dale B. Cooper likes his coffee &#8220;Black as midnight on a moonless night&#8221;</figcaption></div>
<section class="article__box">
<div class="article__box-text">
<div>
<p>Okay, so what about quality? Famously, big enterprise products are big on features and big on bugs:<sup id="fnref-7558-4"><a href="#fn-7558-4" class="jetpack-footnote">4</a></sup></p>
<blockquote><p>
  A bug in Microsoft Word was exploited by hackers for months before it was eventually fixed, according to security researchers. The flaw allowed attackers to take control of a computer via malicious document files.&#8221; – <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-39732490">BBC</a>.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Bugs are creepy by nature, but when big apps and OSes have them they feel almost natural. Android is free, it has a million features and it&#8217;s from a big corporation. So it has big bugs. Who are we to complain about losing apps and data when updating to Android 12? Shit happens! And at this scale: Bring a lot of toilet paper!</p>
<p>Instead of blaming Android for bugs, indie apps should find ways to avoid them, step dance around them. After all, they just write text to disk, so how hard can it be to dance a little? Life is not always fair. Luckily, there&#8217;s nothing a good, hot cup of coffee can&#8217;t fix. So let&#8217;s get back to grinding beans.</p>
<h2>How many apps does a coffee cost?</h2>
<p>Unless we&#8217;re talking in Java, the comparison coffee:software doesn&#8217;t make any sense. Yeah, they both cost money. But so does almost everything. But, then again, like the smell of a good arabica, it&#8217;s not easy to resist. Sometimes, I indulge. It happens when I buy stuff. Especially when I buy coffee. I construct that loathed comparison from my side of the fence. <strong>For me, the question is not: How many coffees does an app cost. It&#8217;s: How many apps does a coffee cost?</strong> So, when I buy a cup of coffee, I do ask myself: &#8216;How many apps do I need to sell to buy that very cup? 1, 2, 20, 200?&#8217;<sup id="fnref-7558-5"><a href="#fn-7558-5" class="jetpack-footnote">5</a></sup></p>
<p>I am not making this up. When I hand out my 1, 2, 20, 200 apps for that cup of coffee, my next thought is usually that it would probably be smarter to wait, go home, and brew my own.<sup id="fnref-7558-6"><a href="#fn-7558-6" class="jetpack-footnote">6</a></sup> But&#8230;</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Every day, once a day, give yourself a present. Don’t plan it, don’t wait for it, just let it happen. It could be a new shirt in a men’s store, a catnap in your office chair, or two cups of good, hot, black coffee.&#8221; –Dale B. Cooper
</p></blockquote>
<p>I usually end up thinking something along the lines of: &#8216;You must have miscalculated somehow! You can pay your rent after all! That must be millions of apps! And you don&#8217;t sell millions of Apps.<sup id="fnref-7558-7"><a href="#fn-7558-7" class="jetpack-footnote">7</a></sup> You know that you can afford a cup of coffee! This is a spell! Apps are not coffee!&#8217;</p>
<p>So, finally, I send the spell of the coffee-cup-comparison to where it belongs and get myself my aromatic present.</p>
<p>The bottom line is: We both completely under- and oversell our apps. To some people our software is of crucial importance, they would pay way more (and they even say so), to others their value is close to 0 (and they say so, too). Because, man, apps are not coffee! iA Writer is not a cup of coffee, it&#8217;s a&#8230;</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div class="article__img"><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Lucca-M58-Stainless-Espresso-Machine-Hero.png" alt="Apps are coffee makers!" width="" height="" class="" /><figcaption>Ceci n&#8217;est pas une application. </figcaption></div>
<section class="article__box">
<div class="article__box-text">
<div>
<h2>&#8230;a Coffee Maker!</h2>
<p>If there is a valid coffee comparison it&#8217;s the coffee maker.<sup id="fnref-7558-8"><a href="#fn-7558-8" class="jetpack-footnote">8</a></sup> Productivity apps are not consumed. Productivity apps are tools. They help you make things. Great apps help you make nice things. Pro apps help you make pro things. How could a text editor compete with an espresso machine?</p>
<p>Yes, in the end, all editors just make text. Just as, in the end, all coffee makers just make coffee. We all know that some coffee makers are easy and fast and make average coffee. Some are easy and make good coffee. Some are a lot of work and make excellent coffee. Some are a lot of work and the coffee tastes like soup. And so do apps! Coffee makers, not cups of coffee.</p>
<p>If you buy a good espresso machine, but you don&#8217;t care how to handle it, your coffee will pour out as a thin soup. Same for apps. Buy a common all-in-one machine if you don&#8217;t care about coffee.<sup id="fnref-7558-9"><a href="#fn-7558-9" class="jetpack-footnote">9</a></sup> If you use cheap beans or grind them wrong, the best machine will not make up for it. If you have nothing to say, the best, most focused writing app can&#8217;t help you.</p>
<p>Of course, you can complain about the price of anything as much as you want, but what is crystal clear: Good coffee needs a good machine, good beans, a good grinder, and skills. If you can&#8217;t taste the difference, go for the all-in-one machine.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn-7558-1">
The crawling one that software developers make when they want you to buy a subscription. They try to look easy like Sunday morning but then end up sounding like underperforming real estate salesmen trying to play old tricks on a late Friday evening. You know: Coffee is for closers.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-1">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-2">
If you don&#8217;t work in the industry it&#8217;s a mystery why it costs something to begin with. Click a bit on a keyboard, and it sells by itself. Unlike growing coffee, apps scale, cost-free, infinitely! No one knows and no one cares about the cost of designing, developing, supporting, and managing an app.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-2">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-3">
Most likely you get some oily blueprint of a database-generated unfelt niceness that has been optimized for numerical customer satisfaction.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-3">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-4">
Android and iOS have some spectacular unfixed bugs on the system level. Google Slides often requires you to type the first letter of a new paragraph twice. It&#8217;s a bug that has been plaguing Slides for over a year. Who cares! Not to sound bitter, but indie apps that have such bugs get&#8230; deliciously roasted.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-4">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-5">
A subscription for Android is $5 per year, which is, plus-minus Google&#8217;s share, less than 35 cents per month. Okay, apps for one coffee. Then I deduct production cost, and I get closer and closer to the sun. Start at 20 apps&#8230; add design&#8230; 60 apps&#8230; development&#8230; 100 apps&#8230; marketing&#8230; 150 apps&#8230; and&#8230; wait&#8230; 200 apps for one cup of coffee!? What is this madness?&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-5">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-6">
200 apps, one cup can&#8217;t be. It&#8217;s just too obscene.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-6">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-7">
At least not every month. In 11 years, we&#8217;ve sold over three million apps. Unfortunately, we sold most of them at a time where they cost 1 dollar. Note: The profitability was always more or less the same. For some reason, the elasticity of apps is so high that no matter what price you ask for, you always end up with the same profit.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-7">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-8">
But the computer is the coffee maker! And that&#8217;s why it, indeed, costs 1,500. Right? No! This is my analogy! And in <em>my</em> analogy, the computer is the kitchen, and iA Writer is a coffee maker. Here&#8217;s the difference though: A good espresso machine costs between $1,500 and $25,000.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-8">&#8617;</a>
</li>
<li id="fn-7558-9">
Get Microsoft Word if you want an all-in-one app.&#160;<a href="#fnref-7558-9">&#8617;</a>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/on-apps-and-coffee">On Apps and Coffee</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7558</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do Presentations Make You Anxious?</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/topics/do-presentations-make-you-anxious</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Reichenstein]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 11:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?p=7513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We’ve been locked away, a cabin in the mountains, working on the problem of presentations. And it’s time to invite a few more people around the fire, to participate in the process. What’s your perspective on the problem? </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/do-presentations-make-you-anxious">Do Presentations Make You Anxious?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’ve been locked away, a cabin in the mountains, working on the problem of presentations. And it’s time to invite a few more people around the fire, to participate in the process. What’s your perspective on the problem? We’d love to hear from you.</p>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x-1024x439.png" alt="Raise the iA Flag" width="100%" height="" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-7516" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x-1024x439.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x-300x129.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x-768x329.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x-1536x659.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/iA-Flag-2@0.5x.png 2034w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<section class="article__box">
<div class="article__box-text">
<div>
<ul>
<li>If presentations are an important part of your job…</li>
<li>If you can’t sleep the night before you have to present…</li>
<li>If you find presentations a weird and unnatural way to communicate…</li>
<li>If presentations are a time suck, for you or your team…</li>
<li>If presentations are costing you, financially or emotionally…</li>
</ul>
<p>Can we help you move beyond the pain of presentations? We’d love to listen. And we’d love to share what we’ve been working on. But only with a select few, people who find presenting a real problem.</p>
<p>Interested? <a href="https://forms.gle/Dht8CLvUMbi2S8z18">Apply here</a>. You can <a href="https://twitter.com/iapresenter">follow us on Twitter</a>, now, too.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/do-presentations-make-you-anxious">Do Presentations Make You Anxious?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7513</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Markdown in Academic Writing</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/writer/blog/markdown-in-academic-writing</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krisztina Zala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 04:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?post_type=ia5_writer_posts&#038;p=7451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A piece of writing aiming to be academic must be 'clear, concise, focused, structured and backed up by evidence'. We believe that Markdown writing tools make it easier to focus on content and thus support the main aim of academic writing. iA Writer has a couple of tricks up its sleeves that other apps do not.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/markdown-in-academic-writing">Markdown in Academic Writing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A piece of writing aiming to be academic must be <a href="https://library.leeds.ac.uk/info/14011/writing/106/academic_writing">&#8216;clear, concise, focused, structured and backed up by evidence&#8217;</a>. We believe that Markdown writing tools make it easier to focus on content and thus support the main aim of academic writing. iA Writer has a couple of tricks up its sleeves that other apps do not.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-6924 size-full" src="http://stagingx.ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/4.png" alt="" width="2370" height="1600" /></p>
<h2>Why Markdown?</h2>
<p>Here is a short summary of the technical and creative advantages Markdown brings to Academic Writing, and how iA Writer boosts them.</p>
<h3>Lightweight files</h3>
<p>Hundreds of pages <a href="https://vimeo.com/264315873">load faster</a> in Markdown than in commonly used word processors, placing considerably less strain on your device.</p>
<h3>Future-proof format</h3>
<p>Since Markdown is plain text with rich text elements, it is future-proof; it doesn&#8217;t matter if your tool of choice is discontinued, you will be able to open and work with your file using other editors anytime.</p>
<h3>Focus on Content and Structure</h3>
<p>Markdown makes us think about what we say and how we structure it. Word Processors heavy on formatting, too much chrome and automation have the tendency to make us play with fonts, colors, margins, and fancy features rather than doing the work.</p>
<p>Academia rarely requires documents to be submitted in <code>.md</code> format. iA Writer has this covered: the app offers HTML, MS Word (<code>.docx</code>) and <code>.pdf</code> export. iA Writer offers the most complete Markdown to Word import/export parsing around.</p>
<h3>Foolproof file sharing</h3>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t matter if co-authors have different writing apps, since Markdown files can be edited in any of them. Its straightforward styling options are a huge plus for file sharing efficiency, as advanced styling debates can be postponed until the finished work is exported to Word. Mind you, we believe that the text formats Markdown offers are perfect for the majority of academic fields.</p>
<h2>Academic Paper design templates</h2>
<p>There are various design templates circulating for academic papers. These ensure that the design specifics of your paper, such as fonts, spacing, headings, citations, and so on, comply with relevant academic standards. You can download the most common template from the <a href="https://ia.net/downloads#templates">iA Writer site</a>. With a bit of HTML, CSS or JavaScript knowledge, you can create your own template in iA Writer. See our <a href="https://github.com/iainc/iA-Writer-Templates">guide on Github</a>.</p>
<h2>How does iA Writer help academics?</h2>
<p>Markdown helps users focus on writing instead of browsing formatting options. This is useful in the context of lengthy academic papers. iA Writer doubles down on focus thanks to its clearcut interface, handy key binds, and the original Focus Mode that keeps attention on the sentence or paragraph the user is typing at any given moment.</p>
<p>iA Writer was designed for creating uncluttered, focused, and concise text. This core alignment with Academic Writing requirements is supported by Syntax Highlight and Style Check features.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ia.net/writer/support/writing-tips/parts-of-speech">Syntax Highlight</a> helps you spot possible instances of exaggeration which should be avoided in academia. It can help you track consistent and clear word usage.</li>
<li><a href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/introducing-style-check">Style Check</a> points out clichés, fillers, and redundancies, assisting users in creating content that is to-the-point, formal, and professional.</li>
</ul>
<p>From correspondence with our users, we know you have written short and long academic papers, even your <a href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/after-all-everyone-is-distracted-once-in-a-while">thesis</a> with the help of iA Writer. We encourage you to message us with your relevant experiences. How has Markdown and iA Writer helped you in academic writing? What were the greatest advantages? Have you encountered any limitations? Do you have templates you used and are happy to share with us? We&#8217;d love to share your tips and insights with fellow students, researchers, and scientists.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/markdown-in-academic-writing">Markdown in Academic Writing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7451</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After all, everyone is distracted once in a while</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/writer/blog/after-all-everyone-is-distracted-once-in-a-while</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krisztina Zala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 03:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?post_type=ia5_writer_posts&#038;p=7420</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>These days we all fight to stay focused. People with ADHD are specialists on the matter. We asked you to share your experiences with iA Writer. Answers revolved around the topics of distractions and the ability to focus, which are key concerns of the attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Let's see how iA Writer helps you tackle the challenges of writing as explained by users with ADHD. Their insights can help us all.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/after-all-everyone-is-distracted-once-in-a-while">After all, everyone is distracted once in a while</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, let us say thank you. In our recent piece, <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/an-adhd-friendly-writing-app"><strong>An ADHD-friendly Writing App</strong></a></span> we asked you to share your experiences with iA Writer. A lot of you have taken the time to answer, and we are grateful for it. Grateful for the chance to see the process through your eyes, to receive confirmation that what we do is helpful, and to find points on which we might improve our product.</p>
<p>While you praised the default font or made remarks about the UI/UX (thank you for both), most answers revolved around the topics of distractions and the ability to focus, which are key concerns of the attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Let&#8217;s see how iA Writer helps you tackle the challenges of writing as explained by users with ADHD.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-7421 size-full aligncenter" src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink.png" alt="" width="3200" height="1800" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink.png 3200w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink-300x169.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink-1024x576.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink-768x432.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink-1536x864.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/userfeedback-adhd-idontthink-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 3200px) 100vw, 3200px" /></p>
<h2>Keeping distractions to a minimum</h2>
<p>Users explained that a main issue with ADHD is that &#8220;it feels like working with limited short term memory.&#8221; If a task, such as transforming a text into bullet point list, interrupts an ongoing process—writing your text—people with ADHD get distracted more easily than others. In your usual text editor, the number of menus and options is a rabbit hole into distraction-land and away from productivity. iA Writer, on the other hand, shrinks interrupting tasks &#8220;to their smallest possible memory consumption.&#8221; This has helped many a user finish their writing tasks from emails to work and study assignments. As Mirko added, &#8220;I don&#8217;t think I would have been able to write the theory part of both my BA and MA Thesis without iA Writer at all. (&#8230;) to complete a task like these is the real success for an ADHD-brain.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Anti-distraction features</h3>
<p>iA Writer is deliberately minimalist, which makes it easy to use, beautiful, and as distraction-free as possible. Below are the features that our users with ADHD confirmed are efficient in tackling distractions from the writing flow:</p>
<p><strong>No menu bar, features are kept hidden.</strong> An empty page might seem daunting at first, but you&#8217;ll soon find that the complete lack of distractions helps you to focus on finding your words—just like our respondents did.</p>
<p><strong>Markdown formatting.</strong> Daniel finds it useful that adding/removing a heading is only a matter of adding/removing a few characters, as it does not take him away from the text itself.</p>
<p><strong>Distilled feature set.</strong> A key observation of users with ADHD was that the difficulty of applying themselves to one task was further aggravated by the extensive visual formatting options of common writing tools. Carefully limited options to do things liberate us, as they reduce the number of distractions from the task at hand.</p>
<p><strong>Shortcuts.</strong> Again, keyboard shortcuts for frequently used formatting and navigation options save you from having to leave your text for the menu bar.</p>
<h2>Focus is king</h2>
<p>Many of you wrote about the experience that people with ADHD can have great difficulty applying themselves to one task and the myriad of visual enhancement options in commonly used writing apps distract them from putting their thoughts onto the screen. This means that focus-enhancing features can be virtual lifesavers for ADHD productivity.</p>
<h3>Pro-focus features</h3>
<p>iA Writer was designed with focus in mind. This round of feedback has confirmed that Focus Mode is useful for people with ADHD. Here are the settings that help you focus on writing:</p>
<p><strong>Run the app in Full Screen Mode.</strong>  This helps limit external distractions. Andy, for instance has found it useful to shut out bouncing icons in the Dock or the clock in the menu bar.</p>
<p><strong>Use Focus Mode.</strong> Does your ADHD come with perfectionism? If so, Focus Mode can be crucial in reducing the temptation to continuously re-read and tweak your text.</p>
<p><strong>Use Dark Mode.</strong> We suggest you test whether dark letters on a white background or light colors on dark help your immersion best. Maybe this is what you are missing to be able to focus.</p>
<p><strong>Use Syntax Highlight.</strong> Some of you mentioned that ADHD can be helpful if you manage to immerse yourself into a special task. Then people with ADHD can focus more than others. While Syntax Highlight adds more color and visually looks more busy, it strengthens your focus on the text structure and help immersion. It helps you identifying superfluous adjectives, adverbs and makes you think about the text instead of something else.</p>
<p><strong>Use Style Check.</strong> Style check is not a school master telling you this is bad and that is bad. It makes you reflect on what you have written, if you mean it or if you wanted to say something else. Try it out, it, again, can tremendously help you focus and allow to immerse yourself into the text.</p>
<h2>Journal-ready</h2>
<p>Bullet journals can help people with ADHD stay organized and mindful. Naturally, journaling nowadays is often done digitally, and people have different requirements regarding the platform they might use for the purpose. One of our users, Daniel wrote that he intends to keep his bullet journal for decades, and explained why he finds iA Writer right for task:</p>
<p><strong>Not a proprietary hosted data format.</strong> The future of the developer will not affect your access to your files. You can export your documents anytime in other formats and you host your own data on your device or in the cloud.</p>
<p><strong>Syncable data.</strong> Thanks to iA Writer&#8217;s connectivity features, it is possible to sync documents between your devices (i.e. between Mac and iPhone via iCloud, between your Windows laptop and Android phone via Dropbox or Google Drive). This helps park your thoughts (as suggested by ADHD experts) anytime without fear of losing the information.</p>
<h2>Better for people with ADHD, better for everyone</h2>
<p>We&#8217;ll finish the round-up with Willem&#8217;s words. He reported that he finds iA Writer great and uses it for a variety of tasks from writing texts and emails to creating lesson drafts. Moreover, he habitually recommends iA Writer to his Motion Graphics students because of the Reading Time feature: it helps get length of voice-overs right and avoid distractions when writing. &#8220;Not all of them have ADHD of course, but it helps them anyway.&#8221; Remember, ADHD is not a black and white diagnosis. These days we all fight to stay focused. People with ADHD are specialists on the matter. Their insights can help us all.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/after-all-everyone-is-distracted-once-in-a-while">After all, everyone is distracted once in a while</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7420</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Style Check on Android</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-android</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krisztina Zala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 04:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?post_type=ia5_writer_posts&#038;p=7356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After its launch on Mac and iOS last summer and its recent introduction to Windows, Style Check has arrived on Android with version 2.1 of iA Writer. It has been one of our best received and most requested features, therefore we worked hard to make it available for all platforms.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-android">Style Check on Android</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After its launch on Mac and iOS last summer and its recent introduction to Windows, Style Check has arrived on Android with version 2.1 of iA Writer. It has been one of our best received and most requested features, therefore we worked hard to make it available for all platforms.</p>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and-1024x965.png" alt="" width="1024" height="965" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-7358" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and-1024x965.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and-300x283.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and-768x724.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and-1536x1447.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/lt-dk-and.png 1594w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>Why do you need Style Check? As William Strunk Jr. put it in The Elements of Style,</p>
<blockquote><p>
  A sentence should contain no unnecessary words, a paragraph no unnecessary sentences, for the same reason that a drawing should have no unnecessary lines and a machine no unnecessary parts.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Style Check helps you refine your work with suggestions optimized on large bodies of text. It doesn’t tell you what is right, but it makes you think about what you say. It grays out superfluous words and strikes them through hypothetically, so you can see how your text will flow with them removed.</p>
<p>In version 2.1, you find Style Check in the menu, where you can now toggle not only Dark Mode, Focus Mode and Word Count, but Style Check, too. When you first turn on Style Check, it will mark all filler words, redundancies and clichés in your text. You can choose to show or hide any of these categories in the Settings. There, you can also set the language of Style Check to English, German or French.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, you can add your own custom patterns, i.e. turns of phrase you wish to mark and avoid. Don&#8217;t forget, you decide which Style Check suggestions to accept or discard. They are simply suggestions. The feature is not designed to cut your words, it is honed to help you consider them closely, until your text flows just right.</p>
<p>Would you like to know more about the methodology behind Style Check? Read our introductory post about the feature to <a href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/introducing-style-check">know more</a>.</p>
<p>Try Style Check now: if you are using iA Writer version 2.0.1, you can upgrade to 2.1 for free in Google Play. If you have an earlier version, but you’d still like to try Style Check without commitment, there is a 30-day in-app free trial in Google Play. Purchasing the new app is also worthwhile, since 2.1 includes more productive features, such as collaboration and Style Check, and all future updates will be free, too.</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who downloaded or plans to download iA Writer: an app is nothing without its users. We love to get feedback from you, so we can keep optimizing iA Writer for its actual, real-life use cases. Don’t hesitate to <a href="mailto:writer+featurerequest@ia.net?subject=iA%20Writer:%20Feature%20Request">drop us a message</a> about your experience with the app or even about the dream feature you think the app is missing.  If you want to immerse yourself even more into improving iA Writer, you can sign up to the ranks of our beta tester team by <a href="mailto:support+beta@ia.net">sending us an email</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-android">Style Check on Android</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7356</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An ADHD-friendly Writing App</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/writer/blog/an-adhd-friendly-writing-app</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Krisztina Zala]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?post_type=ia5_writer_posts&#038;p=7316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There is a ton of specialist advice out there regarding writing for high school and university students with ADHD. Most of these suggest a distraction-free writing environment that allows for channeling one's energy into the task at hand.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/an-adhd-friendly-writing-app">An ADHD-friendly Writing App</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is a ton of specialist advice out there regarding writing for high school and university students with ADHD. Most of these suggest a distraction-free writing environment that allows for channeling one&#8217;s energy into the task at hand. Setting and rewarding clear goals is important too.</p>
<p>What rarely gets a mention is: when using a typical word processor, the above requirements can hardly be met. Consider the UI of such applications: there are myriad options on the menu bar, distracting the writer from the text. Not to mention the cornucopia of formatting possibilities, which again deter the user from getting the work done &#8211; because clearly, the text looks better with this other font, in this color. Or should I arrange this in a bullet point list? Then again&#8230;</p>
<p>You see where we&#8217;re going.</p>
<p>iA Writer&#8217;s minimalistic interface, on-page word count, and analytic features were crafted to keep the focus on the text. They cut out noise during the working process and, in turn, the content. These features were not built specifically with ADHD in mind, but design that minimizes distraction is beneficial for all.</p>
<p>For some time now, we received clear feedback from family and friends that were diagnosed with ADHD that with iA Writer they can write in a more focused way. It&#8217;s a small highly subjective sample, but it made us wonder if there is more to it. How does iA Writer help people with ADHD? What do our users say? Can you help us finding out more?</p>
<h2>How does iA Writer help people with ADHD?</h2>
<h3>Uncluttered Interface</h3>
<p>Once you start typing, iA Writer removes menus and window dressing from sight. You are left with your text and the word count, meaning that there are no distractions on the page.</p>
<h3>Markdown Formatting</h3>
<p>The app uses Markdown, an easy way to format your content using plain text. You need not click menus or leave the page to create headings or bold/italic text, so your attention does not wander from the writing. You can format your entire document without your hands ever leaving the keyboard. It is a true digital typewriter. Of course, the formatting options are accessible via the menu bar as well.</p>
<h3>Focus Mode</h3>
<p>iA Writer&#8217;s Focus Mode highlights the sentence or paragraph you are working on by slightly fading out the rest, thus helping you focus on one idea at a time. This works both in normal and dark mode. Here is a screenshot of this function:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7377" src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1.png" alt="" width="100%" height="auto" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1.png 2370w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1-300x196.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1-1024x669.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1-768x502.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1-1536x1003.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/dk-w-count-1-2048x1338.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2370px) 100vw, 2370px" /></p>
<h3>Word Count</h3>
<p>Setting a clear writing goal, such as a specific number of words, helps people with ADHD remain focused on their assignment. iA Writer has a built-in word count. In our Windows version users can follow the number of words completed in relation to the goal set (e.g. 180 / 250 words). This helps the writer keep track of their progress, never leaving the page.</p>
<h3>Syntax Highlight and Style Check</h3>
<p>These modes show the syntactic and stylistic properties of the text, helping users think about what they write. They can be switched on and off if you prefer to focus on writing first then styling next. Once you&#8217;ve knocked out a first draft, you can turn these on to aid you in fine-tuning the text.</p>
<h3>Feedback from users with ADHD</h3>
<p>User feedback suggests iA Writer works for a number of people with ADHD, too.</p>
<p>“iA Writer takes over your whole screen and makes me focus on the content of what I’m saying, NOT on the fonts, the layout, or any other distracting features. In a simple courier-style font, on a basic background, iA Writer forces you to concentrate and just get down to writing.” via <a href="https://smartgirlswithadhd.com/">Smart Girls with ADHD</a></p>
<p>“Users can even turn on focus mode so that only the sentence or paragraph being worked on is visible, making it a great tool for writers who struggle with any type of attention challenges such as ADHD, executive functioning, and other focused-based learning disabilities.” via <a href="https://athelpdesk.org/">AT Helpdesk</a></p>
<p>Naturally, an app (or two) will not solve the challenges of living and thriving with ADHD, but the right technology or UX design can eliminate some of the obstacles.</p>
<h2>Help us finding out more</h2>
<p>If you have ADHD or if you experience trouble focusing with traditional text editors, we&#8217;re looking forward to hear about your experience with iA Writer!</p>
<p>If you do research in the field and you&#8217;d like to work with our apps, don&#8217;t hesitate to get in touch with us.</p>
<p>iA Writer works on several platforms, Mac/iOS, Windows, and Android, and you can download them <a href="https://ia.net/downloads">here</a>. Most of them have free trial periods, so you can take a distraction-free test-drive.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/an-adhd-friendly-writing-app">An ADHD-friendly Writing App</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Style Check on Windows, Big Sur Support, and Next Steps for Android</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-windows-big-sur-support-and-next-steps-for-android</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[@iawriter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?post_type=ia5_writer_posts&#038;p=7238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>iA Writer for Windows 1.4 is now available and it brings Style Check in a free update. We launched Style Check on Mac and iOS this past summer and we have never received so much praise for a new feature. You sent us request after request to bring it to other platforms. We doubled our efforts to bring it to other platforms as soon as possible. It's ready for Windows as of today. We are working on bringing it to Android next.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-windows-big-sur-support-and-next-steps-for-android">Style Check on Windows, Big Sur Support, and Next Steps for Android</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win.png" alt="Style Check on Windows" width="100%" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7257" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win.png 1920w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win-300x169.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win-1024x576.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win-768x432.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/style-check-win-1536x864.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></p>
<h2>Style Check on Windows</h2>
<p>iA Writer for Windows 1.4 is now available and it brings Style Check in a free update. We launched Style Check on Mac and iOS <a href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/introducing-style-check">this past summer</a> and we have never received so much praise for a new feature. You sent us request after request to bring it to other platforms. We doubled our efforts to bring it to other platforms as soon as possible. It&#8217;s ready for Windows as of today. We are working on bringing it to Android next.</p>
<p>You can find Style Check in the Focus menu in version 1.4, alongside Syntax Control. There you can choose to mark filler words, redundancies and clichés in your text. You can add your own custom patterns if there are turns of phrase you wish to mark and avoid.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll see that 1.4 includes a swathe of other improvements including a faster start up time and a brand new splash screen. If you are running a more recent version of Windows you&#8217;ll see improved window borders and menus, too.</p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t updated to 1.4 already, please restart iA Writer and you&#8217;ll be prompted to install the free update. And if you&#8217;ve been waiting for Style Check on Windows before making the jump, you can download the free trial <a href="https://ia.net/writer/windows/trial/download">here</a>.</p>
<h2>Support for macOS Big Sur</h2>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur.png" alt="iA Writer on Big Sur" width="100%" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7239" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur.png 4096w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur-300x158.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur-1024x540.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur-768x405.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur-1536x810.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/bigsur-2048x1080.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4096px) 100vw, 4096px" /></p>
<p>If you have been holding out updating to Big Sur, you needn&#8217;t worry about how iA Writer will perform there. Last month we released support for Big Sur and Apple silicon. iA Writer now runs natively on the M1 chip.</p>
<p>As another nicety, in version 5.6.3 we added an option to resize the window when showing and hiding the Library. It is something many of you have asked for and we&#8217;re happy to deliver it:</p>
<div style="width: 1920px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-7238-1" width="1920" height="2064" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Resize-window-to-show-Library.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Resize-window-to-show-Library.mp4">https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Resize-window-to-show-Library.mp4</a></video></div>
<h2>Application Passwords in WordPress 5.6</h2>
<p>WordPress 5.6 was released <a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2020/12/simone/">earlier this month</a> and contains an exciting new feature: application passwords. All previous versions required a plugin to authorize iA Writer to publish drafts on your blog. Now authentication is built into WordPress itself. Starting with iA Writer 5.6.7, new WordPress.org accounts in iA Writer must use application passwords. You can continue using accounts you added earlier, but we strongly recommend upgrading your WordPress installation, disabling the authentication plugins, and adding the accounts again using application passwords, because a built-in authentication method should be more secure.</p>
<h2>Next Steps for Android</h2>
<p>Today, we rolled out version 2.0.1 of iA Writer for Android. This is primarily a maintenance release which addresses an issue with accessing the Public folder in Android 10 along with adding stability improvements. We also moved Library-specific settings into the Library itself. This means even with the freely downloaded version you will be able to sort your documents as you prefer.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re excited about Android&#8217;s recent revitalization and are pushing to bring new features soon. Our next release, 2.1, is under active development and in that we will bring Style Check to this platform too. It functions the same as elsewhere, allowing you to create custom patterns for fillers, redundancies and cliches in addition to the included checks.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/writer/blog/style-check-on-windows-big-sur-support-and-next-steps-for-android">Style Check on Windows, Big Sur Support, and Next Steps for Android</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7238</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple cuts 30% commission to 15% for small developers</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/topics/apple-cuts-30-commission-to-15-for-small-developers</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Reichenstein]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 11:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?p=7216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Apple will lower its commission to 15% if you make under one million US dollars per year. For small developers, this is fantastic news and overall it’s a good step in the right direction. In the bigger picture, more steps need to follow.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/apple-cuts-30-commission-to-15-for-small-developers">Apple cuts 30% commission to 15% for small developers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/To-be-or-not-to-be-in-Apples-terms.png" alt="" width="" height="" class="logo" /></p>
<p>Apple will lower its commission to 15% if you make under one million US dollars per year. For small developers, this is fantastic news and overall it&#8217;s a good step in the right direction. In the bigger picture, more steps need to follow.</p>
<p>Apple will be lowering its sales commission to 15% for developers that make under one million US dollars per year. Apple <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/11/apple-announces-app-store-small-business-program/">states</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Existing developers who made up to $1 million in 2020 for all of their apps, as well as developers new to the App Store, can qualify for the program and the reduced commission. </li>
<li>If a participating developer surpasses the $1 million threshold, the standard commission rate will apply for the remainder of the year. </li>
<li>If a developer’s business falls below the $1 million threshold in a future calendar year, they can requalify for the 15 percent commission the year after.</li>
</ul>
<p>As we have <a href="https://ia.net/topics/monopolies-apple-and-epic">argued before</a>, asking for 30% of your revenue in our industry is unreasonable. Making software, 30% is plus-minus the maximum you can expect in profits. At that margin, <a href="https://ia.net/topics/subscription-or-no-subscription">successful startups are kept small, and average performing startups will fail</a>. 15% is still high, but one can run a business at that margin. Clearly, this is a step in the right direction and it&#8217;s fantastic to know that <a href="https://ia.net/topics/how-to-think-different">Apple still supports people that think different</a>.</p>
<p>As great as this is for small developers, and as much as this is a first-class PR move&#8230; Apple&#8217;s concession doesn&#8217;t change <a href="https://ia.net/topics/why-is-facebook-not-paying-the-apple-tax">the big picture</a>. Small to medium-sized companies (at 1M revenue you are still small) are still held back to grow to bigger companies.</p>
<p>The second thought developers will have after &#8220;Wow! Cool! Finally!&#8221; will be: &#8220;Oh, and what if we cross the 1M threshold?&#8221; As great as it is to make $999,999.–, the moment when you cross that line, you&#8217;re back at ＄700,000.–. And from there it&#8217;s the old uphill struggle to grow.</p>
<p>There are other implications, as, for instance:</p>
<ul>
<li>Companies, like us, that are working on a brand new app, will think about founding another corporation to avoid the one million threshold and lose out on integrating the two apps together. User experience suffers as a result.</li>
<li>Companies that get close to 1 Million in revenue before Christmas, will probably take their apps offline to not cross the threshold.</li>
<li>Companies will be inclined to sell their Mac apps directly to raise the ceiling for their iOS apps.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are many ifs and whats, but in the end, this is a really great first step in the right direction, Apple. Thank you. Now, let&#8217;s take the next.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/apple-cuts-30-commission-to-15-for-small-developers">Apple cuts 30% commission to 15% for small developers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">7216</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why is Facebook not Paying the Apple Tax?</title>
		<link>https://ia.net/topics/why-is-facebook-not-paying-the-apple-tax</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Reichenstein]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 13:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ia.net/?p=6932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why should Facebook—the biggest beneficiary of the iPhone, its tools, and its infrastructure—pay nothing, when small developers have to pay tens and hundreds of thousands of dollars?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/why-is-facebook-not-paying-the-apple-tax">Why is Facebook not Paying the Apple Tax?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why should Facebook—the biggest beneficiary of the iPhone, its tools, and its infrastructure—pay $99.-, when small developers have to pay tens and hundreds of thousands?</p>
<p>The short answer is that Facebook&#8217;s apps belong to the free with advertising category, which Apple defines as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  These apps are free for users to download and the developer generates revenue from advertisements in the apps. Apple receives no commission from supporting, hosting, and distributing these apps. Example Apps: <em>BuzzFeed, Instagram, Pinterest, Twitter</em> – <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/app-store/principles-practices/">Apple</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>Last week Mark Zuckerberg, social media monopolist extraordinaire, complained about Apple abusing its monopoly. Apple, he said, &#8220;blocks innovation&#8221; and abuses its monopoly to ask for &#8220;monopoly rents&#8221;.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  &#8216;[Apple has] this unique stranglehold as a gatekeeper on what gets on phones,&#8217; Zuckerberg said to more than 50,000 employees via webcast. He added that the Cupertino, California–based company’s app store &#8216;blocks innovation, blocks competition&#8217; and &#8216;allows Apple to charge monopoly rents.&#8217;” – Mark Zuckerberg via <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/zuckerberg-apple-monopoly">Buzzfeed News</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>The irony is that <strong>Zuckerberg is the biggest profiteer of Apple&#8217;s platform and he doesn&#8217;t pay rent.</strong> Here are the top 10 Apps on iOS. Three belong to Mark Zuckerberg:</p>
<ol>
<li>YouTube</li>
<li><strong>Instagram</strong></li>
<li>Snapchat</li>
<li>TikTok</li>
<li><strong>Messenger</strong></li>
<li>Gmail</li>
<li>Netflix</li>
<li><strong>Facebook</strong></li>
<li>Google Maps</li>
<li>Amazon</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>From the top 10 only Netflix and Amazon Pay rent.</strong> (They found a backdoor to pay less). Zuckerberg makes billions of dollars selling his ads for free. Why is he complaining? What happened?</p>
<blockquote><p>
  On Thursday, Apple refused to allow Facebook to notify people that the iPhone maker would collect 30% of in-app purchases made through a new feature on the Facebook app that lets businesses sell tickets to online events on the platform.&#8221; – <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/pranavdixit/zuckerberg-apple-monopoly">Buzzfeed News</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>He doesn&#8217;t complain because he cares about innovation. <strong>What he cares about is that <a href="https://variety.com/2020/digital/news/facebook-paid-online-events-apple-tax-1234735547/">Apple is starting to tax Facebook</a>.</strong> And that he is not allowed to complain about it. There is another reason:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Facebook now faces a major obstacle: the next version of iOS, Apple’s operating system, which offers users much more complete information about how apps track their information. With a warning on your smartphone asking you to choose between ‘Allow tracking’ or ‘Ask app not to track’ your advertising ID (IDFA), it’s likely that the number of users who will choose to allow tracking will plummet&#8221; – <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/enriquedans/2020/08/30/privacy-facebook-faces-new-challenges-and-apple-virtuesignals/">Forbes</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>Apple deserves praise for enforcing privacy. And if you think their logic through, <strong>shouldn&#8217;t big apps pay the Apple tax like everybody else?</strong> Small and medium apps are paying hundreds of thousands of dollars and struggle to stay in the black, while the apps that make the biggest profits pay nothing. Why exactly does it matter that they sell advertisement?</p>
<p>In the court case against Epic, Apple claims that it deserves a share of money made through the iPhone. We don&#8217;t need to accept that, but, say, for the sake of the argument, we did: why is not everyone taxed then? Why is Facebook taxed on in-app purchases for concert tickets and not for advertising? Wouldn&#8217;t taxing everyone allow Apple to lower the taxes? Do these old rules from a different time hold in 2020?</p>
<h2>1. Who pays?</h2>
<p>Apple taxes companies that use its platform. And their <a href="https://ia.net/topics/monopolies-apple-and-epic">30% tax <em>is</em> high</a> if you look at the profitability in today&#8217;s software industry. Selling software you are looking at an average profit marking of 20%. If you deduct 30% additional cost from your revenue, you are at minus 10% that you need to catch up with every month.</p>
<p>Apple argues that developers pay for security, tools, and quality. We do not need to because of &#8220;supermarkets&#8221;, because it&#8217;s fair or logical or a good deal. A tiny fraction of the money made via iPhone is being taxed. <strong>The big profiteers of Apple&#8217;s security, tools, reach and platform do not pay.</strong> Apple discerns eight cases and it gives the following examples:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Free</strong> Amazon Alexa, Chase Mobile, Geico, Wikipedia</li>
<li><strong>Free with advertising</strong> BuzzFeed, Instagram, Pinterest, Twitter</li>
<li><strong>Free with in-app purchase</strong> Candy Crush Saga, Clash of Clans, Skype, TikTok</li>
<li><strong>Free with physical goods and services</strong> Airbnb, Amazon, Lyft, Target</li>
<li><strong>Free with subscription</strong> Bumble, Calm, Hulu, Pandora</li>
<li><strong>Paid</strong> Dark Sky Weather, Facetune, Heads Up!, Monument Valley 2</li>
<li><strong>Reader</strong> Amazon Kindle, Audible, Netflix, Spotify</li>
<li><strong>Cross platform</strong> Dropbox, Hulu, Microsoft Word</li>
</ol>
<p>Apple asks for a tax on certain products for historical reasons. And Apple continues to asks for its tax as it does because Apple can. It makes the rules. Apple sees three main cases: Digital goods, physical goods and services, and advertising. These fall into two groups: Paid or subscriptions. They added two special cases: Readers and Cross Platforms where Apple allows users to access apps and content that was paid from somewhere else.</p>
<h3>1.1 Digital goods</h3>
<p>Apple proudly claims that &#8220;hundreds of thousands of developers&#8221; made 40 billion dollars directly through the App Store. <strong>75% of all revenue is generated by games. The remaining cake is eaten up by big earners.</strong> This is how the top 1% of app publishers generate 80% of all new installs, and 95% of all revenue is generated by 1% of the apps:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Out of a total $22 billion in gross revenue generated during Q3 2019, the 1,526 publishers comprising the top 1 percent generated $20.5 billion. Meanwhile, just $1.5 billion, or 7 percent, or all revenue was left over for the 151,056 publishers in the bottom 99 percent. That averages out to a little more than $9,900 per publisher per quarter.&#8221; &#8211; <a href="https://sensortower.com/blog/top-one-percent-downloads">Sensortower</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>The Apple tax applies to apps that, according to Apple, sell digital goods. A lot of popular apps you spend money with, like Uber, pay nothing. This is great for them, but it&#8217;s not that great for the others that are taxed excessively.</p>
<p>The App Store makes 50-60 billion dollars in direct transactions. This is double of what Android makes. In spite of it 13% market share, the iPhone makes twice the revenue compared to Android. iPhone users are at least 10 times more valuable than Android users. <strong>If Apple&#8217;s customer base is 10 times more likely to buy an app, how much more likely are they to spend money on anything?</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>
  On average, Android users spend $11.54 per transaction. iPhone users, on the other hand, spend a whopping $32.94 per transaction. – <a href="https://moz.com/blog/apple-vs-android-aov">Do iPhone Users Spend More Online Than Android Users?</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>So, then let&#8217;s look at the bigger chunks of the e-cake: physical goods/services, and then let&#8217;s try to get a taste of the biggest chunk: advertisement.</p>
<h3>1.2 Physical goods and services</h3>
<p>Last year, the figure for all e-commerce transactions in the App Store was 519 billion dollars per year. That&#8217;s 1/7th of the 3.5 trillion online economy.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Because Apple only receives a commission from the billings associated with digital goods and services, more than 85 percent of the $519 billion total accrues solely to third-party developers and businesses of all sizes. –<a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2020/06/apples-app-store-ecosystem-facilitated-over-half-a-trillion-dollars-in-commerce-in-2019/">Apple</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Half a trillion dollars are measurably made via iPhone Apps that do not pay any percentage of all.</strong> Apps selling services involving physical services, like Uber or Airbnb do not pay the 30% tax to Apple. Uber and Airbnb are proud IT companies. Uber&#8217;s iPhone App is a core asset of their business model.</p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s get to the free ride that the top 10 apps get. They profit most from Apple&#8217;s infrastructure and they make the biggest chunk of money through the iPhone and they pay as much as nothing to Apple.</p>
<h3>1.3 Advertisement</h3>
<p>How much of the 3.5 trillion cash in IT do Facebook, Google, Amazon &amp; Co make through the iPhone, circumventing the Apple tax like they circumvent regular taxes?</p>
<p>If 519 billion dollars are made via iPhone by selling physical goods without being taxed, how much of all the digital goods are channeled through the iPhone without taxes? The ad revenue generated by top iPhone apps, from Facebook, Google, and Co is not available as a clean-cut number. If the general rule of thumb is that an iPhone user is worth ten Android users, then iPhone economically outshines Android in every way.</p>
<p>But they are not digital goods and they are not being sold directly through the apps. If they had in-app payments, Apple would charge them. Right?</p>
<p><strong>Ads are digital goods. What else are ads? Spiritual goods? They are <em>the</em> digital good.</strong> They are what is driving the digital economy in the first place! And, yes, <strong>Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and so on do have direct transactions built into the apps.</strong> And, no, they do not pay any fees to Apple for these in-app transactions.</p>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook-1024x674.png" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6956" width="1024" height="674" alt="" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook-1024x674.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook-300x198.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook-768x506.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook-1536x1011.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Facebook.png 1850w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram-1024x674.png" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6965" width="1024" height="674" alt="" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram-1024x674.png 1024w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram-300x198.png 300w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram-768x506.png 768w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram-1536x1011.png 1536w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pay-Instagram.png 1850w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p>If you buy ads in Facebook via Facebook they&#8217;re Apple tax free, because they are ads. The rules are the rules. If you buy concert tickets for offline events they&#8217;re direct payments and Apple tax free because they are ads and they sell physical services. But if you buy tickets for <em>online events</em> in Facebook via Facebook, they get processed via Apple&#8217;s standard in app purchases. They unlock a function. Then Facebook (in the name of the ticket seller) has to pay 30% to Apple. The UI then looks like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/img_7909.jpg" class="size-full wp-image-7029" width="600" height="338" srcset="https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/img_7909.jpg 600w, https://ia.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/img_7909-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<p>Apple keeps repeating that the rules are the same for all, but they are not. The top ten apps do sell digital goods and only two of the top ten apps pay Apple. Netflix and Amazon. Netflix and Amazon have found a backdoor to avoid the 30% tax. <strong>One difference between ad-based and those who pay Apple is that paid apps charge consumers. Ad based apps feed on our privacy and charge companies for it.</strong></p>
<p>That can be right. So that can&#8217;t be, right? There must be a mistake. We must be missing something. We have been on the App Store for 10 years, paying the Apple tax like a good Apple citizen. We started listening up when Hey raised concerns in May and thought: &#8220;Hey, that&#8217;s courageous, and the attention may be good for you, but Apple will hate you, and you are not going to get Apple to lower the tax.&#8221; When Epic protested, we were glad that someone with power brings it up, but, again &#8220;there is no way you are going to get Apple to lower the tax.&#8221;</p>
<p>We are now investigating the matter for two weeks, and the more we understand, the less we comprehend how no one has pointed out the smoking gun yet. Last Friday, Marco Arment raised <a href="https://overcast.fm/+R7DV02KMM/1:09:00">the same concern</a>. No one is perfect. Epic is far from immaculate. Both Hey and Epic have a point that <strong>there is something rotten in the state of the App Store. The rules need to be rewritten.</strong></p>
<h2>2. Why do we pay?</h2>
<h3>2.1 Tools and infrastructure</h3>
<p>When Apple defends the 30% revenue share they take, one popular argument is that they make the hardware, provide the tools and the infrastructure for developers to publish apps.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  The App Store is not simply a marketplace &#8212; it is part of a larger bundle of tools, technologies and services that Apple makes available to developers to develop and create great applications for iPhone, iPad and other Apple products. [&#8230;] &gt; Epic has made great use of Apple-provided tools, such as TestFlight, VOIP, Stickers, iCloud document storage, ARKit, Messages Extension, ReplayKit, and Push Notifications., such as TestFlight, VOIP, Stickers, iCloud document storage, ARKit, Messages Extension, ReplayKit, and Push Notifications.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Developers have pointed out that we pay 99 dollars a year to Apple for membership and access to those tools. That&#8217;s not much. But that&#8217;s the deal.</p>
<h3>2.2 The marketplace</h3>
<p>In the case against Epic, Apple&#8217;s General Counsel argues that:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Not only has Apple supplied tools and technologies for Epic to build its apps, but it also provided a marketplace—the App Store—to help make them a success.
</p></blockquote>
<p>That same argument applies to the top ten apps. But they don&#8217;t pay a share of their revenue for that.</p>
<h3>2.3 Safety and privacy</h3>
<p>Another line of argumentation is that Apple&#8217;s infrastructure provides a safe environment for its users:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  The guiding principle of the App Store is to provide a safe, secure and reliable experience for users and a great opportunity for all developers to be successful [&#8230;] Apple invests significant resources to ensure that apps meet high standards for privacy, security, content, and quality; we have reviewers located on three continents, representing 81 languages, and reviewing on average 100,000 submissions per week.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Indeed. iOS <em>is</em> safer than Android. One key reason is that Android users don&#8217;t update their devices regularly. Another is that it has a smaller market share. The App Store with its safety check has a huge influence, but not only is iOS safer than Android. The Mac is safer than Windows, and it does allow installing apps without going through the App Store. <strong>With its notarization process, the Mac offers a perfect example of how iOS could work.</strong> It&#8217;s not 100% foolproof, but neither is the App Store: Google &#8220;VPN scam&#8221;.</p>
<p>As for privacy, let&#8217;s look at the top 10, and casually judge them by the standard of privacy. Content and quality are in the eye of the beholder, but when it comes to privacy none of the most popular apps, except Netflix and Amazon stand out:</p>
<table>
<colgroup>
<col style="text-align: left">
<col style="text-align: left">
<col style="text-align: left"></colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align: left">Rank</th>
<th style="text-align: left">App</th>
<th style="text-align: left">Privacy</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">1.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">YouTube</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">2.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Instagram</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">3.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Snapchat</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">4.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">TikTok</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">5.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Messenger</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">6.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Gmail</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">7.</td>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Netflix</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">8.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Facebook</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">9.</td>
<td style="text-align: left">Google Maps</td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align: left">10.</td>
<td style="text-align: left"><strong>Amazon</strong></td>
<td style="text-align: left">?</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>With iOS 14, Apple is going to increase privacy regulation. Great. <strong>This won’t change that the business model of the key apps stands in direct opposition to Apple&#8217;s claims about quality, privacy, and safety.</strong> And yet they are not just the most popular apps, they are the most successful, financially.</p>
<h3>2.4 &#8220;You only pay for digital goods&#8221;</h3>
<p>Apple&#8217;s legal and PR team must have an airtight argumentation at hand, of why ads are not digital goods. As far as we can see, the ads are digital goods. And, as shown above, these digital goods are offered directly through in-app purchases.</p>
<h3>2.5 Historical Reasons</h3>
<p>There are good historical reasons why things are as they are. Initially, Apple decided to charge Apps that were paid or had in-app payments. Apps that were free for end-users and financed themselves through apple were always free from the Apple Tax. This is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=3950&amp;v=MfQtnQHLNcs&amp;feature=emb_logo">how Steve Jobs argued</a>. And, as always, it is convincing. He makes 70% look generous. But this was a long time ago. The App Store lottery is history. Things have changed.</p>
<h3>2.6 Apple needs Instagram, Amazon, Uber, and Google Maps</h3>
<p>A more convincing reason why the top apps do not pay taxes is that Apple needs them as much as they need Apple. The iPhone without Instagram is like Instagram without iPhone. In spite of Apple&#8217;s Championship for privacy and Facebook&#8217;s championship for destroying privacy, the relationship between Instagram and Apple is a perfect symbiosis. An iPhone without YouTube? Possible, but for some exactly not as much fun. An iPhone without Facebook and Messenger? The iPhone would be a better place without them, just as the world would be a better place without Facebook, but, <strong>right now, Apple still needs Facebook just as Facebook needs Apple.</strong></p>
<h3>2.7 Licensing agreements</h3>
<p>There are licensing agreements, like the one between Google and Apple, where <strong>Apple gets 10% of Google&#8217;s general search revenue by selling them the default setting to be the search engine on Safari.</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>
  According to analyst Rod Hall (via Business Insider), Google may be paying Apple upwards of $9 billion this year to remain the default search engine for Apple’s Safari browser on iOS. Hall believes that this number will only continue to grow, potentially leading to a payment of $12 billion in 2019. – <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2018/09/28/google-paying-apple-9-billion-default-seach-engine/">9to5Mac</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>There are strong dependencies between Apple and the IT-Giants. <strong>Amazon gets a special deal, Netflix, Spotify, and similar &#8220;Reader&#8221; apps have found a backdoor to pay less.</strong> Google pays the Apple tax via Safari Settings. Uber and Airbnb get away without paying anything.</p>
<h2>3. You don&#8217;t know the Power of the iPhone!</h2>
<p>Comparing App Stores, it becomes clear why iPhone&#8217;s user base is over 10 times more valuable that the Android user base. Having a fraction of Android&#8217;s market share, Apple&#8217;s App Stores outsells Android&#8217;s stores by factor two. This is why Google pays 10% of its search revenue to Apple, every year.</p>
<p>Now, we are getting towards the treasure chamber on our Indiana Jones Adventure. Let’s first jump over a trap and solve this riddle: If Apple&#8217;s customer base is 10 times more likely to buy an App. How much more likely are they to spend money on anything?</p>
<blockquote><p>
  On average, Android users spend $11.54 per transaction. iPhone users, on the other hand, spend a whopping $32.94 per transaction. – <a href="https://moz.com/blog/apple-vs-android-aov">Do iPhone Users Spend More Online Than Android Users?</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>The global e-commerce economy is estimated at 3.5 trillion. 0.5 trillion are measurably made via iPhones. How much is made in total? How much of those 3.5 trillion do Facebook, Google, Amazon &amp; Co make through the iPhone?</p>
<p><strong>In spite of its tiny market share of 13%, the iPhone has economic leverage that creates a dependency for every IT company that sells physical or digital goods over the Internet.</strong> Physical, digital, advertisement—Apple holds the key to the biggest spenders.</p>
<ol>
<li>We spend 50% more time on the phone than on desktop <a href="https://mindsea.com/app-stats/">Mindsea</a></li>
<li>Mobile Users spend 85% of their time in Apps, versus 15% on the Web <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/Article/eMarketer-Unveils-New-Estimates-Mobile-App-Usage/1015611">emarketer</a></li>
<li>Apple users outspend Android users by factor 3 <a href="https://moz.com/blog/apple-vs-android-aov">Moz.com</a></li>
<li>Apple makes twice as much money in the App Store as Android</li>
</ol>
<p>Apple does not just command over 2/3 of direct App Store revenue. The iPhone is the door to the global IT economy. <strong>The IT economy has moved to mobile, and the people that are most likely to spend money on mobile phones on Apps, in the browsers, anywhere, are iPhone users.</strong> This is the true power of Apple in 2020.</p>
<ul>
<li>They don’t need collusion to instate the same App Store sales commissions everywhere. They set the bar without talking to others.</li>
<li>They don’t really need Epic. They need to make sure that everyone stays in line.</li>
<li>They don’t really need Spotify&#8217;s or Netflix&#8217; share. It&#8217;s just better for them to have their competitors in an iron grip.</li>
</ul>
<p>As long as the biggest earners on iPhone, Google, and Facebook, don&#8217;t pay a share, the 30% sales commission is a theatre that distracts from a much more important power. <strong>If you want to make money online, you need Apple more than they need you.</strong></p>
<p>Now we can dwell both in admiration and ask ourselves: What are the conditions, what are the consequences, and what are the limits of all this power?</p>
<h2>4. Apple shouldn&#8217;t do the job of our governments</h2>
<p>Apple Watch, Apple TV, Apple Music, Apple Pay, Apple Glasses, Apple Cars&#8230; Apple is rumored to work on Apple Search. If Apple replaces Google Search in Safari, Google would save 12 Billion Dollars, but it would massively suffer.</p>
<blockquote><p>
  Part of Google’s mobile search success relies on the fact that it’s the default search engine for the iPhone. The company has paid billions for that privilege over the years. But there’s evidence that Apple might be building a search engine to take on Google – for real this time. <a href="https://searchengineland.com/is-apple-getting-real-about-search-and-about-to-take-on-google-339893">Search Engine Land</a>
</p></blockquote>
<p>At the same time, Apple starts charging Facebook for in-app purchases and starts tightening the privacy screw. <strong>If you paid attention, you see that there is a tectonic shift in IT.</strong></p>
<p>Apple has, without any doubt, a monopoly. It&#8217;s not defined in market share but in revenue share. From a consumer perspective, it&#8217;s just hard to be angry with Apple. Apple devices are expensive, but at the same time, they&#8217;re great. Apple&#8217;s engagement for privacy (IDFA) and user convenience (Apple Pay) make it attractive to us as consumers.</p>
<p>At the same time, arguing about the logic of Apple&#8217;s own laws and their ethical and economic conditions, we forget that <strong>it should not be up to Apple to decide how free we are as citizens.</strong> This is what we have governments for. And, analogously, governments, not Mark Zuckerberg, should protest, step in and make sure that Apple is not building and abusing its monopoly and asking for &#8220;monopolistic rents&#8221;.</p>
<p>This is not a time where the government gets a lot of trust. It&#8217;s easy to get cynical and give up on democracy. But systemically, it should be our parliaments, not board members, that make sure that companies, including Apple, pay taxes. That the 70% coming back from Apple usually is paid from low tax havens is just as ironic as a monopolist that complains about monopolies.</p>
<p>Ultimately, if Apple allowed installing apps without App Store, it would get hard to argue that they abuse their monopoly. All things considered, we don&#8217;t need to blindly accept that Apple has a right to all revenue made from its devices. But if we do accept it for the sake of the argument, then everyone making money through the iPhone should be taxed, especially the bigger apps.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net/topics/why-is-facebook-not-paying-the-apple-tax">Why is Facebook not Paying the Apple Tax?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ia.net">iA</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">6932</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
